Guide to the Johnson family papers, 1776-1937
Johnson family papers, 1776-1937
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Johnson family papers, 1776-1937
4928
Johnson family.
1.9 cubic feet.
Correspondence, wills, diplomas, a field book, an examination, obituaries, marriage certificates, photographs, a book of autographs, pay rolls, land grant certificates, military documents, genealogical notes, family histories and records, books, and other documents of the Johnson family.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Johnson Family Papers consist of correspondence, wills, diplomas, marriage certificates, obituaries, photographs, genealogical notes and family histories, land grant certificates, military documents, a book of autographs, and other papers and documents of the Johnson and related families, direct descendants of the Presidential Adams family. The family was located chiefly in Utica, New York.
REMARKS OF THE DONOR, SARAH JOHNSON
It is an accident of birth that my sister and I had these documents in our possession. It is not, however, an accident that we have chosen to donate them to the Carl A. Kroch Library here at Cornell. Over the years my sister and I have had a number of discussions about the deposition of these papers. Our first concern was preservation. Here in this facility our family records will be stored in a climate-controlled vault, kept as safe as humanly possible from floods, fire, earthquakes, and insects. Second, we wished to make the documents available to others. Here scholars and students will have the opportunity to work with the original documents rather than from a microfilm or xerox copy of them. Already undergraduate students have had a chance to read the family correspondence of John and Abigail Adams in its original form. Holding such a document in one's hands can alter one's sense of history; legendary figures come alive, they become human. And we could not have asked for greater access than to have the letters posted on the world-wide web. Kroch has admirably addressed our fundamental concerns.
Equally important to us was the character of the institution in which we placed the documents. It is understandable that so much of the interest in the collection is focused on the Adams' letters. But the Adamses, distinguished though they were, are only one branch of our family. The letters they wrote originated in Quincy, but their destination was Utica, New York. The history of the other branches of our family is embedded in that of this region. The archives here at Kroch already contain evidence of their presence here, their ties through marriage, commerce, politics and friendship with other families in the area. One of those many ties was to the Cornell family itself. Our grandfather's sister, Mary Savage Johnson, was a friend of Ezra Cornell's daughter, as the inscription in Mary Emily Cornell's autobiography testifies.
Beyond what the documents may reveal about specific individuals and Upstate New York, the collection also reveals, in our view, something about our nation. Three branches of our family were victims of religious persecution. Abigail Adams' ancestors were Puritans who set sail for the New World on the Mayflower; the Savages were French Huguenots; and the Johnsons were Sephardic Jews. All were driven from their homes at some point in their history and came here, we imagine, in search of peace and tolerance, conditions necessary for them to prosper. Let us hope that our country continues to extend this promise to people of all religious and ethnic backgrounds.
On a very personal level this occasion is a somewhat sad one for me. My sister and I have no children. Those of you who have children and grandchildren can envision your family extending into the future, while our immediate family stands behind, not in front of us. Last fall I carried the two tin boxes containing the fragile paper relics of our ancestors to this Library and left them here. By placing these papers in the care of one of the finest research libraries in the world, my sister and I believe we have ensured that the children of the future, both those who can trace their ancestors back generations and those who do not know even their parents' names, will be able to examine the papers and learn something about who we are as a people.
The sadness I have occasionally felt over relinquishing these papers has been outweighed a thousandfold by the pleasure I have received as a consequence of this gift. It has been great fun working on the collection with the superb staff of this facility. The reactions of students and others who have seen the papers have been tremendously gratifying. And it has given me special satisfaction to make this gift to Cornell. During quieter moments, usually on my walk home from campus, I look around and feel the same wonder I felt when I first arrived. I have been so fortunate to be a member of this community of scholars striving for intellectual excellence. Cornell is a truly extraordinary institution. My sister and I could have found no finer home for our family's papers.
By placing these papers in the care of one of the finest research libraries in the world, we have attempted to ensure that they will be preserved and that others will have access to them. We have entrusted them to Kroch with the hope that the children of the future, both those who can trace their ancestors back generations and those who do not know even their parents' names, will have the opportunity to study them and learn something about who we are as a people.
Sarah L. Johnson
Gwyneth J. Lymberis
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Johnson Family Papers consist of correspondence, wills, diplomas, marriage certificates, obituaries, photographs, genealogical notes and family histories, land grant certificates, military documents, a book of autographs, and other papers and documents of the Johnson and related families, direct descendants of the Adams family.
The earliest correspondence concerns the relations between Abigail Adams and her daughter-in-law Sarah Adams, and among other members of the family, including John Adams and John Quincy Adams, Susan B. Adams, Charles Thomas Clark, and various members of the Adams, Johnson, and Savage families. Other documents refer to George Washington, Aaron Burr, Martin Van Buren, and James Monroe. The collection contains much material concerning the genealogy and history of several related families, with reference to their participation in numerous political and social events. The papers include discussion of family relations and matrimony, genealogy, domestic arrangements and social life, family properties and holdings, family political and military history, and other matters. The family was located chiefly in Utica, New York.
Documents are signed by George Washington and James Monroe; genealogies pertain to members of the Johnson, Adams, Smith, Bosch, Het, Quincy, Fowle, Boylston, Shepard, Norton, and Bass families.
Includes letters of daughter-in-law Sarah Adams, John Adams, John Quincy Adams, Charles Adams, Susan B. Adams, Charles Thomas Clark, Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson, Belinda Clarkson, Alexander B. Johnson, Arthur B. Johnson, Aaron Burr, John Savage, Daniel B. Tompkins, Martin Van Buren, Edward Savage, Mary Ann Smith, Louisa C. Smith, Eliza Thompson, Samuel Nelson, Eliza A. Hunt, Mary Ann Savage Hunt, Ward Hunt, and other members of the Johnson, Adams, and Savage families.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Johnson family.; Adams, John, 1735-1826.; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848.; Adams, Abigail, 1744-1818.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Monroe, James, 1758-1831.; Adams, Sarah.; Adams, Charles.; Adams, Susan B.; Clark, Charles Thomas.; Johnson, Abigail Louisa Smith.; Clarkson, Belinda.; Johnson, Alexander B.; Johnson, Arthur B.; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836.; Savage, John.; Savage, Edward.; Tompkins, Daniel D., 1774-1825.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862.; Smith, Mary Ann.; Smith, Louisa C.; Thompson, Eliza.; Nelson, Samuel.; Hunt, Eliza A.; Hunt, Mary Ann Savage.; Hunt, Ward.; Adams family.; Savage family.; Smith family.; Bosch family.; Het family.; Quincy family.; Fowle family.; Boylston family.; Shepard family.; Norton family.; Bass family.
Subjects:
Family - New York (State) - Utica.; Family - Massachusetts - Quincy.
Places:
Utica, New York - Social life and customs.; Massachusetts - Quincy - Social life and customs
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Letters in this collection have been digitized. Links to the digital images can be seen in Series IV.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Adams
Abigail Adams
Box 1
John Adams
Box 1
John Quincy Adams
Box 1
Charles Adams
Box 1
Sarah Adams
Boxes 1, 2, 5
Johnson
Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson
Boxes 2, 5
Alexander B. Johnson
Box 2
William Clarkson Johnson
Box 2
Arthur B. Johnson
Box 2
Savage
John Savage
Box 3
Misc.
Box 12
Series II. Documents
Edward Savage
Boxes 5, 6, 11
John Savage
Boxes 3, 5, 6, 11
Savage family
Box 3
Adams family
Box 4
Johnson family
Boxes 4, 5, 6
Series III. Miscellaneous
Genealogy/Family History
Boes 4, 5, 7
Photographs
Box 4
Miscellaneous Adams, Savage, and Johnson Family Items
Boxes 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, 12
Documents Not Related to the Adams, Savage, and Johnson Families
Box 3
Presidential Signatures
Boxes 5, 4, 6, 11
Series IV. Digital Images
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Adams
    - Abigail Adams
      - Abigail Adams to her daughter-in-law Sarah Adams, 4 letters: February 23, 1806; January 20, 1808; July 3, 1814; December 20, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Abigail Adams to Sarah Adams, 3 letters: April 24, 1816; May 20, 1816; July 28, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Abigail Adams to Sarah Adams, 5 letters: March 20, 1817; April 12, 1817; May 5, 1817; May 28, 1817; August 3, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - A letter from Sarah Adams to Abigail Adams (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Abigail Adams to her granddaughter Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson, 5 letters: July 23, 1811; March 5, 1812; September 9, 1813; October 26, 1814; December 9, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Adams
      - John Adams to his daughter-in-law Sarah Adams, 2 letters: October 26, 1814; October 2, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - A letter from John Adams to his granddaughter's husband Alexander B. Johnson, December 17, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - John Quincy Adams
      - Miscellaneous letters to and from John Quincy Adams, 3 letters - to Samuel Shaw: September 27, 1824; to and from his niece Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson: February 22, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Charles Adams
      - Charles Adams to his brother Thomas B. Adams, 5 letters: May 23, 1790; May 29, 1790; November 21, 1790; August 30, 1791; September 18, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sarah Adams
      - Susan B. Adams to her mother Sarah Adams (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Susan B. Adams to Sarah Adams, 5 letters: July 31, 1816; September 14, 1816; October 3, 1816; March 11, 1817; April 8, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Charles Thomas Clark to his mother-in-law Sarah Adams, 2 letters: May 20, 1816; March 23, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Susan B. Clark to her mother Sarah Adams, 7 letters: July 12, 1826; August 14, 1826; March 10, 1827; March 23, 1827; April 5, 1827; April 30, 1827; May 21, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - A letter from Susan M. Clark to her grandmother Sarah Adams, August 13, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson to her mother Sarah Adams, 3 letters: October 10, 1823; October 22, 1826; October 23, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Belinda Clarkson to her sister Sarah Adams, 7 letters: May 14, 1815; April 1, 1818; May 12, 1818; April 28, 1819; February 24, 1820; September 28, n.y.; November 14, n.y.) (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Margaret de St. Hilaire to her sister Sarah Adams, 4 letters: August 5, 1815; October 3, 1815; November 16, 1815; February 15, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous letters to Sarah Adams, 4 letters - from G. Le Ray de Chaumont: August 15, 1808; Peter Whitney: June 5, 1813; her niece Mary Ann Smith: September 4, 1826; her brother William Smith: n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous letters from Sarah Adams, 4 letters - to her daughter Susan B. Adams: May 10, 1812; her sister Margaret de St. Hilaire: August 19, 1815; her sister Nancy: June 27, 1816; her brother William Smith: February 8, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Ann Masters to her sister Sarah Adams, 2 letters: October 13, 1817; December 22, 1819 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Margaret Smith to her sister Sarah Adams, 2 letters: n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - A letter from James Smith to his aunt Sarah Adams, January 16, 1827 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Johnson
    - Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson
      - Belinda Clarkson to her niece Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson, 4 letters: December 14, 1818; 1820; August 21, 1828; December 13, 1828 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous letters to Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson, 4 letters - from her mother Sarah Adams: July 14, 1811; Elizabeth Peabody: January 20, 1815; her aunt Ann Herrod Adams: September 6, 1815; her cousin Louisa C. Smith: December 16, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous letters to Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson, 4 letters - from Louisa: March 2, 1819; her cousin James Smith: January, 1821; Eliza Thompson: October 12, 1821; her aunt Ann Masters: February 18, n.y.) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - A letter from Alexander Smith Johnson to his mother Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson, July 26, 1831 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Alexander B. Johnson
      - Miscellaneous letters to and from Alexander B. Johnson, 6 letters - from Sarah Adams: September 27, 1825; to Ann Masters: December 4, 1830; to and from Mrs. Ann Breese: December 11, 1830; to Ed. Crufts: August 17, 1842; to Ward Hunt: May 27, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - William Clarkson Johnson
      - Miscellaneous letters to William Clarkson Johnson, 4 letters - from his great aunt Louisa C. Adams: February 22, 1844; Chief Justice Samuel Nelson: March 4, 1844; Attorney General Caleb Cushing: March 24, 1861; W. Phillips: July 27, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Arthur B. Johnson
      - Miscellaneous letters to Arthur B. Johnson including an enclosed letter from the Duke of Wellington to Mrs. Robinson, 2 letters - from Alexander B. Johnson: December 1, 1852; Charles Francis Adams: January 27, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Savage
    - John Savage
      - Correspondence between John Savage and A. Burr, 7 letters: May 12, 1820; June 13, 1820; September 9, 1825; October 16, 1825; January 2, 1827; April 6, 1828; September 28, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Dewitt Clinton to John Savage, 3 letters: July 10, 1816; February 26, 1818; December 31, 1821 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous letters to John Savage, 4 letters - from Governor Daniel D. Tompkins: February 21, 1814; Nat. Cutting: March 24, 1817; J. Montefiore: March 13, 1820; A. Haring: May 23, 1820 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous letters to John Savage, 5 letters - from Harry White: December 14, 1820; John A. Graham: November 26, 1827; Governor Nath. C. Picher: April 17, 1828; H. Clay: April 19, 1828: Jacob Van Ness: April 28, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous letters to John Savage, 5 letters - from his father Edward Savage: April 6, 1829; Governor E. T. Throop: July 4, 1829; Governor W.C. Marcy: December 31, 1832; John A. Dix: November 18, 1835; Martin Van Buren: July 27, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Misc.
      - Photocopies of miscellaneous letters (Box 12)
- Series II. Documents
  - Edward Savage
    - Edward Savage Records: Pay Rolls of Captain Joshua Conckey's Company of Rangers (1776-1777), 4 documents (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Edward Savage Records (1776-1786), 7 documents (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - ... the Secretary's Office, Feb. 16 1784 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Edward Savage Records (1787-1832), 7 documents (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Edward Savage Records: Pay Roll of Captain Joshua Conckey's Company of Rangers (1776), 1 document (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Edward Savage Records: Appointments (1783-1813), 2 documents (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Edward Savage appointment as surrogate, 1783 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - John Savage
    - Records of John Savage: Union College (1799), 2 documents (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Records of John Savage: Oration (1803) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Records of John Savage (1802-1888), 7 documents (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Admission as Counselor at Law, Supreme Court (1806) (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Admission as Solicitor and Councilor at Law, Court of Chancery (1820) (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - "I do here authorize and license him.. ." fourth line down (n.d.) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Records of John Savage (1804-1863), 6 documents (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Commission for the honorable J. Savage as Chief Justice Jan. 29, 1823 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Records of John Savage (1802-1823), 9 documents (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Diploma from Union College: J. Savage 1802 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Savage family
    - Savage Records: Insurance Deeds (1863-1865), 4 documents (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Savage Records: Financial (1815-1865), 5 documents (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Last Will and Testament of John Savage (1863) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Obituaries of John and Ruth Wheeler Savage (1863-1884), 2 documents (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Adams family
    - Poem by Robert Burns to Sally (Sarah) Adams (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Examination taken by Abigail Louisa Smith Adams (1814) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Obituary Notices of Abigail Adams (1818), 2 documents (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Johnson family
    - Field Book by George Webster of John Johnson's property (1796) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Proxy signed by Bryan Johnson, father of Alexander B. Johnson (1818) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Extract from the Autobiography of Alexander B. Johnson: Lafayette (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Obituary Notices of Abigail Louisa Smith Johnson (1836), 2 documents (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Marriage Certificate of Arthur B. Johnson and Eliza S. Hunt (1859) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Last Will and Testament of Alexander B. Johnson (1867) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Obituary Notices of Alexander B. Johnson (1868) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Handwritten obituary notice for Mary Ann Savage Hunt who died in 1846. Believed to be written by Montgomery Hunt Johnson Sr. (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Obituary Notice of Lieutenant John S. Hunt who died in 1864 (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Notices from the Colonial Dames to Eliza S. Johnson (1905-1906), 2 documents (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Three stock certificates belonging to Montgomery Hunt Johnson for shares in Utica Plantations, Inc. and Sconondoa Inn, Inc. (1915-1920) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Johnson Records (1805-1830), 4 documents (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Will and settlements of the estate of Maria T. Hunt, second wife of Ward Hunt (1883-1913) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Wills and settlements of the estate of Eliza S. Johnson (1897-1906), 3 documents (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Documents regarding Ward Hunt Johnson and his trustees Mary S. Johnson and Montgomery H. Johnson (1909-1937), 2 documents (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Johnson Records: Arthur B. Johnson's commission as Commissioner of Railroads signed by President Chester A. Arthur (1882) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series III. Miscellaneous
  - Genealogy/Family History
    - "Semitic Notes": Johnson Family History (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Genealogy of the Johnson, Adams, Smith, Bosch, Het, Quincy, Fowle, Boylston, Shepard, Norton, and Bass Families (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Handwritten Family Record of the Savage, Wheeler, and Hunt Families (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Ancestral Tablets (n.d.)(photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Lyman Family and Wheeler Family Record (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photographs
    - Photograph of the Savage House in Salem, N.Y. (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of the Garden at the Old Johnson House at 235 Genesee St., Utica, N.Y. (n.d.), 4 pictures (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Photograph of Ward Hunt (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Adams, Savage, and Johnson Family Items
    - Lock of John Adams' hair (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Report from the President and Directors of the Ontario Bank. Believed to be written by Alexander B. Johnson (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Edward Savage's New York Pocket Almanac (1790) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - John Savage's "Horse Back Journey" (1817) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Music Book Belonging to John Savage (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Autograph Album Belonging to Ward Hunt Johnson, Includes signatures from R. B. Hayes, Hamilton Fish, M. R. Waite (Chief Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), Nathan Clifford (Assoc. Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), N. H. Swayne (Assoc. Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), Sam. J. Miller (Assoc. Justice- U.S. Supreme Court), David Davis (Assoc. Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), [Stephen Field] (Assoc. Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), W. S. Strong (Assoc. 7 5 1877 (cont.) Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), Jos. P. Bradley (Assoc. Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), Ward Hunt (Assoc. Justice-U.S. Supreme Court), W. A. Wheeler (Vice President), T. W. Henry (President of the Senate of the U.S.), Francis Kernan, Wm. M. Evarts, (Secretary of State), John Sherman (Secretary of the Treasury), Geo. W. McCrary (Secretary of War), R. W. Thompson (Secretary of the Navy), Carl Schurz (Secretary of the Interior ), D. M. Key (Post Master General), Chas. Davis (Attorney General), W. T. Sherman (General), P. H. Sheridan, Wm. M. Evarts, Alexander Stephens, Joseph Henry (President of the Smithsonian Institute), illegible, Wm. Ingraham Kip, John G. Whittier, Th. Nast, William Cullen Bryant, Geo. Bancroft, piece of manuscript with annotation "Part of original of one of Cooper's novels," letter from Alfred B. Street, Henry W. Longfellow, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Donald G. Mitchell, Edwin Booth, Henry Ward Beecher, Celia Thaxter. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook containing charcoal and color drawings, some of which are signed by Laura Savage (1838-1856) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Journal with accounts and essays, possibly belonging to Alexander B. Johnson (1806) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Alexander Bryan Johnson Autobiography, transcribed by Eliza Stringham Morton (1930), Volume I: 1786-1814 Volume II: 1814-1828 (Box 9)
    - Alexander Bryan Johnson Autobiography, transcribed by Eliza Stringham Morton (1930), Volume III: 1828-1839 Volume IV: 1839-1867 (Box 10)
    - Newspaper clippings (1996) (Box 12)
  - Documents Not Related to the Adams, Savage, and Johnson Families
    - Miscellaneous letters (1796-1852), 7 letters - from Montgomery Hunt to his sister Lydia Wheeler: May 12, 1796; Ann Smith to Julia Rush: May 30, 1809; R. W. [Crawmshield] to Dr. J. Mairs: April 4, 1815; M. Hunt to Ephraim Hart: January 21, 1820; Martin Van Buren to Ward Hunt: September 26, 1846; Mrs. [Rainier] to Mr. Hunt: November 16, 1846; [Nath] Sherman to Geo. Peabody: May 27, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Presidential Signatures
    - Discharge of Abraham McKillip signed by President George Washington (1783) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Land Grant Certificates signed by President James Monroe (1817-1818), Grant to Daniel Harrington (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Warrant #4120 to Sylvester Rowley Dec. 19, 1817 (Military) (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Warrant [121] to Eliphalet Peabody Nov. 29, 1817 (Military) (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Warrant #3079 to Benjamin Bailey April 3, 1818 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Autographs of John Quincy Adams (n.d.), 5 envelopes (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Autographed engraving of Ulysses S. Grant (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Johnson Records: Arthur B. Johnson's commission as Commissioner of Railroads signed by President Chester A. Arthur (1882) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Linen copy of the Declaration of Independence (Map Case II-9)
- Series IV. Digital Images
  - Digital Images of the Contents of Box 1
  - Digital Images of the Contents of Box 2